本节课中 我们将介绍操作物体
For this lesson, we're going to cover object manipulation.
本例子中 我们主要介绍
And in this case, we're specifically going to cover
移动 旋转 缩放
position, rotation and scale.
让我们开始吧
So let's get to it.
这里我有3种实体
We have three types of entities here,
先看移动操作
let's go ahead and go to the position.
在这可以看见 有Position字样
Inside of here, we can see that we have a position here,
以及一个正方体
and we have a cube.
墙上也有Position字样
We also have a position over here.
我们的目标是
The name of the game or the goal
把正方体放进墙上的插槽里
is get the cube within this slot inside of this wall.
选中这个正方体
So if I take this cube
使用鼠标左键选中它
and I select it with left mouse button,
按下1键 然后
I can press the 1 key, and I can go...
便可移动它的位置
and I can move the actual position.
我们可以移动Z轴
This can be done in the Z value,
Y轴
the Y value,
X轴
the X value,
或者同时移动多个轴
or we can combine axes
甚至自由移动
ultimately moving all.
继续 移动到墙里
So let's go ahead and move it to the wall.
拖住X轴移动
I'm gonna drag down in the x,
按下G键拉近
and press the G key to zoom in,
然后在Y轴上
and move this to the Y,
向上拉
move it up,
现在应该对准了
and now I'm pretty safe
and sure we'll go in the box, and we have what we want.
把正方体拖进去即可
这就是如何把实体移动到墙中
So that would be a case of positioning an entity within this wall.
我先把帮助器关掉 有点碍事
I'm gonna go ahead and hide the helper, just so we can do this again.
这个例子则是介绍旋转操作
Inside of this, I can see that I want rotation.
选中实体 按下2键
So with this entity, if I press 2,
像之前那样 我可以操纵XYZ轴
just like before I can do the X and Y and Z values,
这里 我得旋转它
in this case, I know that I want to turn it,
我想在X轴上旋转
and I want to turn around on the X.
通常来讲 我可以任意旋转它
So I can move it, generally speaking, wherever I want it to be,
我也可以在属性面板中修改
but I can also come up and set the properties.
修改X轴旋转数值
I can activate the X rotation,
这样就可以插进墙里了
so that we're ready to move this as far as positioning into the wall.
同样 移动过去 G键拉近
So like before, we move it over, and I'm gonna press the G,
移过去
and move this over,
最后移动到墙上
and ultimately we have it position in the wall as well.
下一个是缩放
So next is scale,
这个操作起来有些不一样 因为
and this one's actually a little different, because...
墙上的插槽和盒子不是一个大小
we can notice that our box is not the same size,
按下3键 我们可以放大
so if I press the 3 key, we're able to scale it upward,
在轴上缩放 则可以按非比例的方式
if I press on the axis, I can scale it downward,
向下缩小
in a non-uniform sense.
现在就可以移进去了
So now I have able to slide into the box.
继续把它
Let's go ahead and make it,
拉宽点 有问题的话一会再调整
possibly little wider, who knows, we'll fix it there.
现在按1键移动它
So now we can move it back with the 1 key,
移动到我们想要的位置
to get it to the wall about where we want.
按下G键
I'm gonna press the G key,
我们再调整一下
once again, I'm gonna move this out,
放大一点
scale it up just a little bit,
Z轴向上拉
and move it up in the Z value.
差不多对准了
Looks like we're fairly close,
这样就插进了墙里
now I move it into the wall similar to the others.
这是个很简单的教程 介绍了
So this is a very simple tutorial on how you can use
如何移动 旋转 缩放
position, rotation and scale inside the engine,
以让物体符合大小
to possibly make something conform
或者能放进你想要的位置
or just rotate and slide into an area exactly how you want it.
翻译：他出院了